thealternative.in 2012-12-14

# Privacy Policy | The Alternative

To make use of certain features on our websites, visitors must provide certain information as part of the registration process. (We may ask, for example, for your name, email address, sex, age, and address, and we might request information on your occupation, interests, and the like.) The information you supply will help us to make The Alternative a better website by allowing us to tailor our site to your interests and make it more useful to you. Supplying such information is entirely voluntary. In some instances, which involve, for example, subscriptions, you may need to provide all the information before the subscription can reach you. We can’t deliver your magazines or notify you that you’ve been lucky enough to win a prize in a promotional contest if we don’t know how to contact you. Of course, even if you want to remain completely anonymous, you are still free to take advantage of the wealth of content available on our site without providing any personal information.

We will not sell or make available such information to unrelated third parties.

Our web servers automatically collect limited information about your computer’s connection to the Internet, including your IP address, when you visit our websites. (Your IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet know where to send you data — such as the web pages you view.) Your IP address does not identify you personally. We use this information to deliver our web pages to you upon request, to tailor our websites to the interests of our users, to measure traffic within our websites and let advertisers know the geographic locations our visitors come from. At no point, do we share any specific information.

The Alternative includes links to other websites whose privacy policies we do not control. Once you leave our servers (you can tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you can’t find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from the site’s homepage, you should contact the site directly for more information.

When we present information to our advertisers — to help them understand our audience and confirm the value of advertising on our websites — it is usually in the form of aggregated statistics on traffic to various pages within our sites. If you do register with The Alternative, we may, from time to time, contact you about content and features that we believe may be of interest to you.

All information gathered on The Alternative is securely stored within the The Alternative -controlled database. The database is stored on servers secured behind a firewall; access to the servers is password-protected and is strictly limited. However, as effective as our security measures are, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. And, of course, any information you include in a posting to the discussion areas is available to anyone with Internet access.

A note to end on: The Web is an evolving medium. If we need to change our privacy policy at some point in the future, we’ll post the changes before they take effect. Of course, our use of any information we gather will always be consistent with the policy under which the information was collected, regardless of what the new policy may be.

**Please send your comments, questions or clarifications to contact@thealternative.in.**
